Antonina Pozhogina

Junior Marketing Manager

Germany, Berlin · +49 163 5153876 · aspozhogina@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/pozhogina/

SUMMARY

Junior Marketing Manager with over 5 years of experience in developing and implementing marketing strategies. Working with both B2B and B2C markets, delivered over 100 email marketing campaigns, reaching 40,000 users globally in 50+ countries. Managed content creation and strategy across 11 social media channels simultaneously, ensuring ongoing audience engagement and growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Marketing Manager, DACH Institutions

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

AMBOSS (Berlin, Germany)

MedTech/EdTech company supporting physicians and medical students in their practice.

- Optimized processes using marketing automation tools to improve customer engagement, reducing manual processes by 35% and streamlining workflow.
- Generated warm leads through data-driven digital campaigns, ensuring a strong sales pipeline.
- Executed effective B2B marketing strategies with a focus on client acquisition, user engagement and retention.
- Strategized and implemented email marketing campaigns for B2B customers.
- Developed marketing activities in the DACH region.

B2B Marketing Manager, US & International

Dec 2022 - Oct 2023

AMBOSS (Berlin, Germany)

- Launched 100+ product access campaigns, engaging 40,000 users worldwide.
- Customized e-mail marketing and CRM campaigns in 50+ countries, strengthening the brand internationally.
- Aligned marketing activities with over 30 internal stakeholders, liaising with sales, product, CRM and customer support teams.
- Analyzed and optimized the effectiveness of marketing campaigns using data-driven results, increasing ROI and customer engagement.
- Supported the implementation of B2B marketing initiatives across all continents.

Marketing and Public Relations Manager

Jun 2021 - Nov 2022

RS AlphaCapital GmbH (Berlin, Germany)

FinTech digital asset company.

- Developed and executed marketing strategies for an HNWI-oriented product.
- Led creative initiatives to enhance the company's visual identity, ensuring a compelling brand presence.
- Drove content marketing, putting together content for Linkedin and sales materials.

Public Relations Manager

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

Communication Agency "Spice Media" (St. Petersburg, Russia)

PR-agency providing comprehensive promotion services.

- Managed client outreach, delivering clear communication and nurturing interactions.
- Oversaw the creation and strategized content across 11 social media channels, supporting ongoing engagement and audience growth.
- Compiled detailed performance reports, providing actionable insights.

EDUCATION

- Europa Universität Viadrina, Master's degree in Digital Entrepreneurship, GPA: 1.2, 2023.
- Uniwersytet im. Adama Mickiewicza w Poznaniu, Master's degree in Digital Entrepreneurship (double degree), GPA: 1.2, 2023.
- Saint Petersburg State Electrotechnical University "LETI", Bachelor's degree in Advertising and Public Relations, GPA: 1.3, 2018.

LANGUAGES

Russian: native, English: C1+, German: B2, Polish: B2.

SKILLS

Digital Marketing, Marketing Strategy, SaaS Marketing, Data-Driven Strategies, CRM Marketing, Product Marketing, SMM, SEO, Email Marketing, Growth Marketing, B2B, Project Management, Branding, Communication, Problem Solving.